Guide to the Elizabeth Bishop Papers, circa 1880-2023 (bulk 1929-1979)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES XI. WORKS BY OTHERS
  - Works about Elizabeth Bishop by others
    - Pereira, Lucia Miguel: "Elizabeth Bishop,", undated; (TS (carbon), 4 p.) (Folder 80.4)
    - Pinsky, Robert: "The Idiom of a Self,", undated; (TS (copy), 13 p.) (Folder 80.5)
    - Schwartz, Lloyd: "The Mechanical Horse...,", undated; (TS (copy), 14 p.) (Folder 80.6)
    - Schwartz, Lloyd: "One Art: The Poetry...,", undated; (TS (copy), 24 p.) (Folder 80.7)
    - Summers, Joseph H.: "Elizabeth Bishop" [unpublished lecture given at Oxford in the 1960s; part of a series given by Summers on American poets], undated; (TS (copy), 4 p.) (Folder 80.8)
    - Tapscott, Stephen: [Review of The Diary of "Helena Morley"], undated; (TS (copy), 9 p.) (Folder 80.9)
    - Unterecker, Jack: "Elizabeth Bishop," pp. 1-31, [1978?]; (TS (copy), 31 p.) (Folder 80.10)
    - Unterecker: "Elizabeth Bishop," pp. 32-63, [1978?]; (TS (copy), 32 p.) (Folder 80.11)
    - Unterecker: "Elizabeth Bishop," pp. 64-42-A (new page), [1978?]; (TS (copy), 35 p.) (Folder 80.12)
    - Unterecker: "Elizabeth Bishop," pp. 41 (new page)- 80, [1978?]; (TS (copy), 35 p. with correspondence by Elizabeth Bishop) (Folder 80.13)
    - Vendler, Helen: "Domestication, Domesticity, and the Otherworldly,", undated; (TS (copy), 13 p.) (Folder 80.14)
    - Poems for Elizabeth Bishop, undated; (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 80.15)
  - Works by and about Robert Lowell
    - Letters to Lowell from Marianne Moore, Jack Sweeney, 1957, 1960; (TS, MS) (Folder 81.1)
    - Eye and Tooth/Alfred Corning Clark, undated; (MS, TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.2)
    - Sailing Home from Rapallo, 1954; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.3)
    - Stalin, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.4)
    - The Scream, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.5)
    - Water, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.6)
    - Middle Age/Child's Poem/Autumnal, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.7)
    - The Old Flame, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.8)
    - Caligula, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.9)
    - The Neo-Classical Urn, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.10)
    - Dropping South: Brasil, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.11)
    - Night Sweat, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.12)
    - The Lesson, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.13)
    - Those Before Us (with TLS to E. Bishop), 1963; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 81.14)
    - Imitations, undated; (TS (mimeograph), 67 p.) (Folder 81.15)
    - Life Studies, undated; (TS, 34 p.) (Folder 81.16)
    - Commander Lowell (1888-1949) (Folder 81.17)
    - "To Speak of Woe That Is in Marriage,", undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.18)
    - Man and Wife, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 81.19)
    - Terminal Days at Beverly Farms (Folder 81.20)
    - My Last Afternoon With Uncle Devereux Wilson, undated; (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 81.21)
    - [Fragment], undated; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 81.22)
    - Mother Marie Therese Drowned in 1912, undated; (TS, 3 p.) (Folder 81.23)
    - Memories of West Street and Lepke, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 82.1)
    - To Delmore Schwartz, 1946; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 82.2)
    - Skunk Hour, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 82.3)
    - The Opposite House, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 82.4)
    - The Dolphin, undated; (TS, 60 p.) (Folder 82.5)
    - Three Poems for Elizabeth Bishop, [1970]; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 82.6)
    - Jonathan Edwards in Western Massachusetts, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 82.7)
    - The Kavanaughs of Stewart Mills, 1957; (TS, 3 p.) (Folder 82.8)
    - Facsimiles of drafts of "The Quaker Graveyard in Nantucket," issued by the Houghton Library, 1978 (Folder 122.11)
    - Lowell's Last Poems, by Helen Vendler, undated; (TS, 47 p.) (Folder 82.9)
    - Printed copies of Lowell's poems, 1964, undated; (6 p.) (Folder 82.10)
    - Articles and Reviews about Lowell, 1961,1965, 1973, undated; (50 p.) (Folder 82.11)
    - Obituaries and Memorials for Lowell, 1977 (Folder 82.12)
    - Obituaries for Lowell, 1977 (Folder 122.10)
  - Prose, poetry, and other works by others
    - Andrade, Carlos Drummond de: Acontecimento, (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 83.1)
    - Anonymous Poems, (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 83.2)
    - Berryman, John: O Lithest Shirley and Other Worlds, (TS, 3 p.) (Folder 83.3)
    - Bidart, Frank: [Poems], (TS, 52 p.) (Folder 83.4)
    - Budenz, Julia: [Poems], (TS, 99 p.) (Folder 83.5)
    - Campos, Paulo Mendes: Arenga e Reza de Um Guia de Ouro Preto, (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 83.6)
    - Cummings, e. e: Thanksgiving 1956, 1957; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 83.7)
    - Elliott, G. P.: [Poems], (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 83.8)
    - Ettinger, Elzbieta: Comrade and Lover, (TS, 48 p.) (Folder 83.9)
    - Ettinger, Maia: [Poetry and Prose], 1978; (TS, 5 p.) (Folder 83.10)
    - Fisher, Anna H.: [Poems], [1978]; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 84.1)
    - Galassi, Jonathan: Eugenio Montale: Xenia; [Poems], [1971]; (TS, 19 p.) (Folder 84.2)
    - Gerstel, Alice R.: The Developments in Lake Texcoco, (TS, 7 p.) (Folder 84.3)
    - Gunn, Thom: For Signs, (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 84.4)
    - Heaney, Seamus: [Poems], (TS, 16 p.) (Folder 84.5)
    - Hussey, Anne: [Poems], (TS, 11 p.) (Folder 84.6)
    - Jarrell, Randall: [Poems], (TS, 24 p.) (Folder 84.7)
    - Jeh, William: Cliffhanger, (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 84.8)
    - Kaplan, Peter: [Poems], (TS, 3 p.) (Folder 84.9)
    - Leithauser, Brad: An Expanded Want Ad, (TS, 3 p.) (Folder 84.10)
    - MacIver, Loren: Catalogue of Paintings of Loren MacIver, (TS, 23 p.) (Folder 84.12)
    - McMahon, Eileen: The Pilgrims/ Alone/Walloomsac Depot (Folder 84.13)
    - McPherson, Sandra: Guernseys, (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 84.14)
    - Merrill, James: Epilogue: Birth of the Musician, 1979 (Folder 85.1)
    - Merrill, James: Scripts for the Pageant, 1978; (TS (copy), 57 p.) (Folder 85.2)
    - Mickley, Loretta: The Aquarium at Coney Island: Easter, (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 85.3)
    - Moore, Marianne: It Is Late, I Can Wait, (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 85.4)
    - Moore, Marianne: Apparition of Splendor, 1952; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 85.5)
    - Moore, Marianne: The Jerboa, (MS (hand of E. Bishop), 4 p.) (Folder 85.6)
    - Moore, Marianne: Poems, with ms corrections by E. Bishop [photocopy of originals at The Rosenbach], (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 85.7)
    - Moore, Marianne: The Ichor of Imagination, (TS, 3 p.) (Folder 85.8)
    - Moore, Marianne: Concerning the Marvelous, (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 85.9)
    - Moore, Marianne: What Are Years?; Four Quartz Crystal Clocks; The Wood-weasel; Rigorists; Walking-sticks and Paperweights and Water-Marks, (TS, 7 p.) (Folder 85.10)
    - [Miscellaneous poems], 1941, 1968; (TS, 22 p.) (Folder 85.11)
    - O'Donnell, Mark: [Poems], (TS, 3 p.) (Folder 86.1)
    - Peech, John: [Poems], (TS, 23 p.) (Folder 86.2)
    - Peech, John: [Poems], (TS, 25 p.) (Folder 86.3)
    - Pollitt, Katha: [Poems], (TS, 3 p.) (Folder 86.4)
    - Preston, James: term paper for Bishop class, (TS, 17 p.) (Folder 86.15)
    - Riordan, Tom: Tailor in Relief, 1977; (TS, 22 p.) (Folder 86.5)
    - Rorem, Ned: Conversation, 1957; (music MS, 2 p.) (Folder 86.6)
    - Rorem, Ned: Visits to St. Elizabeth's, 1957; (music MS, 6 p.) (Folder 86.7)
    - Schmidt, Michael: Vineyard, (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 86.8)
    - Soares Regis, Flavio de Macedo: Otatu, (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 84.11)
    - Sternberg, Ricardo: [Poems], (TS, 86 p.) (Folder 86.9)
    - Swenson, May: [Poems], (TS, 7 p.) (Folder 86.10)
    - Talbot, Kathrine: Amongst the British Soldiers, (TS, 18 p.) (Folder 86.11)
    - Thomas, Dylan: [Untitled Poem], (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 86.12)
    - Willemsen, August: [Essay], (TS, 10 p.) (Folder 86.13)
    - Wilson, Edmund: Retrograde Rhymes for YNNUB, (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 86.14)
- SERIES XII. PRINTED MATERIAL
  - Published work by Bishop
    - The Owl (North Shore Country Day School), 1926-1927 (Folder 87.1)
    - Blue Pencil (Walnut Hill School) (2 cop.), 1928 Jun (Folder 87.2)
    - Blue Pencil, 1928 Dec (Folder 87.3)
    - Blue Pencil (2 cop.), 1929 Apr (Folder 87.4)
    - Blue Pencil, 1929 Jun (Folder 87.5)
    - Blue Pencil (2 cop.), 1929 Dec (Folder 87.6)
    - Blue Pencil, 1930 Apr (Folder 87.7)
    - Blue Pencil — Photocopies compiled by Candace MacMahon, (1 TLS, 1 set of photocopies) (Folder 121.10)
    - Blue Pencil — See also Folder 78.7
    - Con Spirito, vol. 1, no. 1, 1933 Feb (Folder 88.1)
    - Vassar Review, 1933 Summer (Folder 88.2)
    - The Magazine, 1934 (Folder 88.3)
    - "Roosters" (2 cop.), 1941 Apr (Folder 88.4)
    - Partisan Review, Fall, 1944 (Folder 88.5)
    - "As We Like It, "The Quarterly Review of Literature, 1948 (Folder 88.6)
    - "A Sentimental Tribute," Bryn Mawr Alumnae Bulletin, 1962 (Folder 88.6)
    - Translations by Bishop, 1964, 1965 (Folder 89.1)
    - Visits to St. Elizabeth's (Music by Ned Rorem, Poem by E. Bishop), 1964 (Folder 89.2)
    - Conversation (Music by Ned Rorem, Poem, by E. Bishop), 1969 (Folder 89.3)
    - The Harvard Advocate (Thank-you Note), Spring 1969 (Folder 89.4)
    - The Harvard Advocate (A Brief Remembrance and a Brief Tribute) (Folder 89.5)
    - "The Fish,", 1974; (broadside; 1 of 12 signed copies) (Folder 106.2)
    - "One Art,", 1976; (broadside) (Folder 89.6)
    - "One Art,", 1979; (broadside; 1 of 200 copies) (Folder 89.7)
    - "North Haven,", 1979; (broadside; no. 49 of 150 signed copies) (Folder 107.2 (Oversize))
    - "North Haven,", 1979; (broadside; no. 1 of 150 signed copies - inscribed to Herb Yellin) (Folder 107.2 (Oversize))
    - The New Yorker (miscellaneous poetry) (Folder 89.8)
    - Miscellaneous Prose (Folder 89.9)
    - Miscellaneous Poetry (Folder 89.10)
    - Interviews with Elizabeth Bishop (Folder 90.1)
  - Translations of Bishop's works and foreign language newspapers
    - O Ladrão da Babilônia [The Burglar of Babylon, translated by Flavio de Macedo Soares Regis], (, undated; (4 p.) (Folder 90.2)
    - Poemas, undated; (TS, 110 p.) (Folder 90.3)
    - Elizabeth Bishop - Antologia (translated by Orlando José Hernandez), undated; (TS, 27 p.) (Folder 90.4)
    - Elizabeth Bishop: Cronologia, undated; (TS, 13 p.) (Folder 90.6)
    - Elizabeth Bishop: En El Poblado, undated; (TS, 33 p.) (Folder 90.7)
    - Entrevista a Elizabeth Bishop, undated; (TS, 15 p.) (Folder 90.8)
    - Foreign Language Newspapers (Folder 91.1)
    - Foreign Language Newspapers (Folder 91.2)
    - Foreign Language Newspapers (Folder 91.3)
    - Foreign Language Newspapers (Folder 91.4)
  - Published reviews of Bishop's work
    - Reviews - North and South (Folder 91.5)
    - Reviews - Questions of Travel (Folder 91.6)
    - Reviews - The Diary of "Helena Morley" (Folder 92.1)
    - Reviews - The Diary of "Helena Morley" (Folder 92.2)
    - Reviews - The Diary of "Helena Morley" (Folder 92.3)
    - Reviews - The Complete Poems (Folder 92.4)
    - Reviews - Geography III (Folder 92.5)
    - Reviews - Geography III (Folder 92.6)
    - Reviews - Geography III (Folder 92.7)
    - Miscellaneous Reviews (Folder 93.1)
    - Miscellaneous Reviews (Folder 93.2)
    - Miscellaneous Reviews (Folder 93.3)
    - Miscellaneous Reviews (Folder 122.9)
    - Reviews - Poemas (1990), a selection of poems from The Complete Poems, 1927-1979 (Folder 97.4 - 97.6)
    - Reviews of works about Bishop (Folder 93.4)
  - Other published material about Bishop
    - Articles About Bishop (Folder 93.5)
    - Articles About Bishop (Folder 93.6)
    - Articles/clippings saved by Bishop's Aunt Florence Bishop and cousin Kay Orr Sargent (Folder 93.7)
    - Commencement Programs, etc. (Folder 94.1)
    - Press Releases (Folder 94.2)
    - Programs - By and About Bishop (Folder 94.3)
    - Programs - By and About Bishop (Folder 94.4)
    - Program - International Poetry Forum Calendar, including a reading by Bishop, 1977 (Folder 122.20)
    - Bishop Memorial Service program, October 1979 (Folder 95.1)
    - Book Jackets and Publicity (Folder 95.2)
    - Miscellaneous clippings related to Bishop and her work (Folder 122.8)
  - Published material by and about individuals
    - Duncan, Robert - "In Memoriam Wallace Stevens,", 1972 (Folder 95.3)
    - "T. S. Eliot," The Harvard Advocate, 1938 Dec (Folder 95.4)
    - "T. S. Eliot," The Harvard Advocate, 1948 Nov (Folder 95.5)
    - Miller, Margaret - "Gericault's Paintings of the Insane,", undated (Folder 95.6)
    - Moore, Marianne - By and About, 1969, 1970, 1972, 1977 (Folder 95.7)
    - Paz, Octavio - "Return,", [1972?] (Folder 95.8)
    - Paz, Octavio - "Discovery of the Present,", 1973 (Folder 95.8)
    - Paz, Octavio - "In Praise of Hands,", 1974 (Folder 95.8)
    - Rorem, Ned - Music of Ned Rorem, undated (Folder 95.9)
    - Shapiro, David - The Page-Turner, 1973 (Folder 95.10)
    - Sternberg, Hilgard O'Riley (Folder 122.18)
    - Summer, Joseph - "Marvell's Nature,", 1951 (Folder 95.11)
    - Summer, Joseph - "Herbert's Form,", 1953 (Folder 95.11)
    - Vendler, Helen - "The Re-Invented Poem: George Herbert's Alterations,", 1970 (Folder 96.1)
    - Wakoski, Diane - "Creating a Personal Mythology,", 1975 (Folder 96.2)
    - Wehr, Wesley -"The Wind and the Rain" (music), 1959 (Folder 96.3)
    - Wilson, Edmund - Wilson's Christmas, 1955 (Folder 96.4)
    - Wilson, Edmund - Wilson's Christmas Stocking, undated (Folder 96.4)
    - Newspaper Articles — By and About Others (Folder 96.5)
    - Programs — By and About Others (Folder 96.6)
    - Reviews of Works by Others (Folder 96.7)
    - Obituaries - Notable Literary Figures (Folder 96.8)
    - The Case of the Three Marias and Novas Cartas Portuguesas (Folder 96.9)
- SERIES XIII. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Bishop: Snapshots and portraits
    - Childhood (Folder 100.1)
      See also: Bishop's baby book in Folder 113.1
    - Bishop with her mother, approximately 1912; (1) (Folder 119.2)
    - Negatives of young Bishop [collected by Alice Methfessel?], (5 negatives) (Folder 119.3)
    - 1930s (Folder 100.2)
    - Sheet of photos [probably removed from an album] from Bishop's education at Vassar College - only one includes Bishop, approximately 1930-1934; (20 images on the front and back of one sheet) (Folder 114.6)
    - Elizabeth Bishop in Key West, 1937; (1) (Folder 119.1)
    - 1940s-1960s (Folder 100.3)
    - Snapshots, 1969-1976, undated; (4 slides, 12 photographs) (Folder 119.1)
    - Passport photos, 1966 and undated; (2) (Folder 100.4)
    - Snapshots, approximately 1960s; (3) (Folder 113.3)
    - Portraits, approximately 1960s; (2) (Folder 113.3)
    - Photographs of portraits by Loren MacIver (Folder 100.5)
      Originals in boxes 108 and 109
    - Snapshot sent to Lilli Correia de Araújo, undated; (1) (Folder 112.15)
    - Negatives of Elizabeth Bishop with cat, with original enclosure, undated; (2) (Folder 113.3)
  - Family
    - Bishop, Bulmer, and Coe families (Folder 100.6)
    - Bulmer [Boomer] family photo album — once belonged to Maud Boomer Shepherdson (Folder 105.5)
    - Unidentified photo album [possibly Gertrude and William Bishop's honeymoon], approximately 1908 (Folder 119.18)
    - Loose items removed from photo album (Folder 119.19)
    - Unidentified family (Folder 119.20)
  - Friends and acquaintances
    - "Calado and wife" with Lota (Folder 100.14)
    - Calder, Alexander (Folder 100.7)
    - Calder, Alexander (Folder 119.6)
    - Crane, Louise (Folder 100.8)
    - Eduardo, Alphonso (Folder 119.6)
    - Fizdale, Robert and Arthur Gold, (3 photos, 2 clippings) (Folder 119.5)
    - Galentine, Wheaton, Harold Leeds, Elizabeth Bishop, and Lota, 1962 (Folder 100.9)
    - Hemingway, Pauline and Marjorie Stevens, 1950 (Folder 100.10)
    - Lowell, Robert (Folder 100.11)
    - Soares, Lota de Macedo (Folder 100.12)
    - Soares, Lota de Macedo, 1944, undated; (14) (Folder 113.4)
    - Soares, Lota de Macedo, undated; (3 photos, 2 clippings) (Folder 119.4)
    - MacIver, Loren (Folder 119.6)
    - MacIver, Loren and Lloyd Frankenberg (Folder 100.13)
    - Methfessel, Alice (Folder 100.16)
    - Methfessel, Alice? (Folder 119.6)
    - Miller, Margaret (Folder 100.14)
    - Moore, Marianne — photos found at Elizabeth Bishop's Lewis Wharf apt. (Folder 100.15)
    - Moore, Marianne — framed photo by George Platt Lynes (Folder 105.3)
    - Morse, Monica Stearns (Folder 100.16)
    - Muser, Frani Blough (Folder 100.16)
    - Saroyan, William (Folder 100.17)
    - Thomas, Dylan [?] (Folder 100.17)
    - Vigo, Fabrica "Farma" (Folder 119.6)
    - Walnut Hill School students, 1928; (2 copies) (Mapcase - Drawer 34)
    - "Boogie" - Child, 1968 Mar (Folder 115.16)
    - Unidentified people (Folder 100.14)
    - Unidentified people (Folder 119.7)
  - Events
    - Elizabeth Bishop at Harvard (Folder 100.18)
    - Elizabeth Bishop at Oklahoma for the Books Abroad/Neustadt Prize, 1976 (Folder 100.19)
    - Elizabeth Bishop at Oklahoma for the Books Abroad/Neustadt Prize, 1976 (Folder 119.1)
    - Elizabeth Bishop at Princeton, 1979 (Folder 100.20)
  - Places
    - Great Village, Nova Scotia, (photos and photo postcards) (Folder 100.22)
    - Worcester, Massachusetts (Folder 100.23)
    - Newfoundland trip, 1932; (photos and photo postcards) (Folder 100.24)
    - Ten Thousand Islands, Florida — canoe trip, 1938? (Folder 119.8)
    - Samambaia, Petrópolis (Folder 100.25)
    - Samambaia, Petropolis, interiors, by Darcy Trigo, (4) (Folder 113.5)
    - Samambaia, Petropolis, interiors, (3) (Folder 113.5)
    - Samambaia, Petropolis, exteriors, (4) (Folder 113.5)
    - Samambaia, Petropolis, house plans by Sergio Vladimir Bernardes, (5) (Folder 113.6)
    - Album of Lota's Samambaia house — taken by later owners, the Torrealba family (Folder 105.4)
    - Samambaia, 1970, 1974 (Folder 119.11)
    - Samambaia and a cat, (negatives) (Folder 119.12)
    - Ouro Prêto: Photo and postcards sent to Lilli Correia de Araújo, undated; (3 postcards and 1 snapshot) (Folder 112.15)
    - Ouro Prêto (Folder 100.26)
    - Ouro Prêto, (slides) (Folder 100.27)
    - Casa Mariana, Ouro Prêto and Petropolis, 1970, 1974 (Folder 119.10)
    - Aterro do Flamengo (Flamengo Park), Rio de Janeiro — plan (Folder 119.13)
    - Rio de Janeiro (Folder 119.14)
    - Elizabeth Bishop's Brazil trips (includes photos of Laura and Aldous Huxley) (Folder 100.28)
    - Miscellaneous (commercially-made) travel slides (Folder 100.29)
    - Elizabeth Bishop's slides of Brazil (Boxes 101-102)
    - Photographic prints of Elizabeth Bishop's slides of Brazil, 2023 (Boxes 101-102 (Photocopies))
    - Brazil [taken by Erich Hess?] (Folder 119.15)
    - Brazil — Miscellaneous (Folder 119.16)
    - Unidentified snapshot, floating platforms in Brazil, (1) (Folder 113.5)
    - "Lewis Wharf (under construction)" (Folder 119.9)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified (Folder 119.17)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Bulletin board with clippings and photos, including shots of Loren MacIver and Lloyd Frankenberg, and Robert Lowell, (1) (Folder 113.7)
  - Art work
    - Elizabeth Bishop's paintings, including paintings not owned by Vassar, (slides) (Folder 100.30)
    - Prints of works of art by Wesley Wehr (Folder 100.31)
    - Paintings included in Exchanging Hats, approximately 1995; (65 slides) (Box 103)
- SERIES XIV. ARTWORK
  - Pieces by Elizabeth Bishop [Photographic prints will be used for research]
    - "43 King Street,", undated (Box 128)
    - "Begonias and Coleus,", undated (Box 103)
    - "Chandelier,", undated (Box 103)
    - "County Courthouse,", undated (Box 128)
    - "Coxcombs,", 1963; [Pastel inscribed to Oscar [Simon]] (Box 104)
    - "Croton,", undated (Box 103)
    - "Fireplace,", undated (Box 103)
    - "Grave with Floral Wreaths,", undated (Box 104)
    - "Graveyard with Fenced Graves,", undated (Box 103)
    - "Interior with Calder Mobile", [with photograph] (Box 104)
    - "Lamp,", 1952 (Box 104)
    - "Mérida from the Roof,", 1942 (Box 128)
    - "Murray Hill Hotel,", undated (Box 103)
    - "Red Stove with Flowers,", 1955; [Inscribed to Magú] (Box 104)
    - "Sha-Sha,", 1937 (Box 103)
    - "Star Cactus,", undated (Box 103)
    - "Table with Plaid Cloth,", undated (Box 103)
    - "Unfinished Fireplace,", undated (Box 104)
  - Pieces by Others
    - Watercolors by Wesley Wehr, (photographic prints only) (Folder 100.31)
    - Pen and ink sketches by Wesley Wehr, (6 sketches) (Folder 107.3 (Oversize))
    - Oil portrait of Elizabeth Bishop by Loren MacIver, (21" H x 20" W) (Box 108 (Oversize))
      [Photographic print in Folder 100.5]
    - Oil portrait of Elizabeth Bishop by Loren MacIver, (22" H x 21" W) (Box 109 (Oversize))
    - Pencil sketches: Anonymous -- Loren MacIver?, (4) (Folder 105.1)
    - Sketches by Flavio [de Macedo Soares], (4) (Folder 105.2)
    - Architectural drawing of Elizabeth Bishop's home in Ouro Prêto (Folder 107.4 (Oversize))
    - Water color, "Goose Rocks Light, North Haven," by Kit Barker, 1979; (7 x 10.25) (Folder 127.11)
    - Architectural drawing of Elizabeth Bishop's home in Ouro Prêto (Mapcase — Drawer 33)
    - "The Ballad of the Burglar of Babylon," woodcuts by Ann Grifalconi (Mapcase — Drawer 37)
- SERIES XV. MEMORABILIA and EPHEMERA
  - High School Annual - Great Village, Nova Scotia, 1914-1915 (Folder 96.10)
  - Blue Star Line - Passenger List, 1964 (Folder 96.11)
  - Map: Sable Island: Graveyard of the Atlantic, 1948 (Mapcase — Drawer 33)
  - Silver Feather award, Books Abroad/Neustadt International Prize for Literature, in wooden box, 1976 (Box 129)
  - Academic hoods (7) -- honorary doctorates (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - Oil lamp from Brazil, blue glass (Box 130)
  - Metal door plate from "Casa Mariana," Bishop's home in Ouro Prêto, Brazil (Box 130)
  - Elizabeth Bishop's slide projector (Box 110)
  - Pages 191-194 of a travel guide to South America, annotated (perhaps from one of her earliest trips) (Folder 113.17)
  - 2 handwritten recipes (chicken tetrazzini and Russian salad) (Folder 113.17)
  - Collection of "Postcards to Save", (1 photograph, 16 postcards - those sent to Elizabeth Bishop are listed individually in Correspondence) (Folder 121.11)
  - Blank postcards, greeting cards, and stationery (Folder 121.12)
  - Postcard sets — "The Fountains of Petrovorets" and "The Parks at Pushkin" (Folder 127.1)
  - 1934 Vassarion stationery — Elizabeth Bishop listed as editor-in-chief (Folder 121.13)
  - Documents from Elizabeth Bishop's first trip to Brazil, 1951; (4 documents, 1 envelope) (Folder 121.14)
  - Charles Darwin Foundation for the Galapagos, 1975; (1 packet of information) (Folder 121.16)
  - Shopping and to-do lists, undated; (2 lists, 1 news clipping) (Folder 121.17)
  - Unidentified woodcuts, inscribed [to Lota?]: "A wood cut from a ballad - from the North -", 1962; (4 woodcuts) (Folder 121.18)
  - Advertising leaflet for Sapolio soap (Folder 121.19)
  - Poland Spring House pamphlet, approximately 1900 (Folder 121.20)
  - Miscellaneous loose items, (1 Algerian stamp, 1 Camel fire cracker wrapper, 1 with compliments card from Mrs T. S. Eliot) (Folder 121.21)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Folder 122.6)
  - Miscellaneous clippings — some annotated by Lota (Folder 122.7)
  - "Miscellaneous Reprints" (Folder 124.14)
  - Lithograph: "Fruits du Bresil" (Folder 125.1)
  - Rio 64: special issue of Manchete - includes section on Aterro do Flamengo, (2 copies) (Folder 125.2)
  - Manchete - special issue on the death of Getúlio Vargas, 1951 Aug 30 (Folder 125.3)
  - Album of cartes de visite — appears to be playwrights and actors, approximately 1880 (Box 126)
  - Scrapbook — Inscribed "To Mary [Ryan?] from her Sister Rosy," includes many trade cards for Poughkeepsie businesses as well as poetry clipped from newspapers, approximately 1880 (Folder 127.2)
- SERIES XVI. PHOTOCOPIES AND REPRODUCTIONS
  - Boxes 1-14 (Photocopies) (PR Box 1)
  - Boxes 15-25 (Photocopies) (PR Box 2)
  - Boxes 26-37 (Photocopies) (PR Box 3)
  - Boxes 38-45, 47, 49 (Photocopies) (PR Box 4)
  - Box 46 (Photocopies) (PR Box 5)
  - Box 48 (Photocopies) (PR Box 6)
  - Boxes 52-60, 64-67 (Photocopies) (PR Box 7)
  - Boxes 68-74 (Photocopies) (PR Box 8)
  - Boxes 75-85 (Photocopies) (PR Box 9)